Robert Winslow Gordon papers
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Robert Winslow Gordon papers 1840-1961 1920-1933
AFC 1928/003
Gordon, Robert Winslow
approximately 22,339 documents
47 containers
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Song texts, correspondence, publications, and fieldnotes collected by Robert Winslow Gordon.
Provenance
Robert Winslow Gordon; Donation; 1928-1932.
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Related Material
Related materials in the Library of Congress's collections:
American Folk-Song Collection: Gordon Manuscripts, 1921-1930 (bound copy of Series 1 from AFC 1928/003)
Robert Winslow Gordon cylinder collection, 1922-1928 (AFC 1928/002)
Robert Winslow Gordon songsters collection, 1844-1886 (AFC 1928/004)
Robert W. Gordon collection of disc recordings, 1932 (AFC 1969/002)
Kodish, Debora G. 'Good Friends and Bad Enemies': Robert W. Gordon and American Folksong Scholarship. MA thesis, Memorial University of Newfoundland, 1977. (AFC 1978/011)
Kodish, Debora G. Good Friends and Bad Enemies: Robert Winslow Gordon and the Study of American Folksong. Urbana: University of Illinois Press, 1986.
Debora G. Kodish collection on Robert Winslow Gordon, 1968-1985 (AFC 2004/019)
Additional papers belonging to Robert Winslow Gordon, primarily folk songs collected by Gordon, can be found in the Robert W. Gordon collection at the University of Oregon Libraries, Special Collections and University Archives in Eugene, Oregon.
Access and Restrictions
The Robert Winslow Gordon papers are open to research. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at https://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Microfilm
A microfilm edition of the Robert Winslow Gordon papers is available on 15 reels in the Music Division at the Library of Congress. The collection is not duplicated in its entirety on microfilm and the arrangement of the physical papers has changed over time and no longer mirrors the arrangement of the papers on the microfilm. Researchers wishing to use the microfilm version of these materials should contact the Performing Arts Reading Room at https://hdl.loc.gov/loc.music/perform.home
Biographical Note
Robert Winslow Gordon was born in 1888 in Bangor, Maine. He studied English at Harvard beginning in 1906, working under George Lyman Kittredge. In 1912 he married Roberta Peter Paul of Darien, Gerogia, and their only child, a daughter named Roberta, was born in 1914. Gordon accepted a position as assistant professor of English at the University of California, Berkeley in 1917. During his tenure as a professor at the University of California between 1917 and 1924, Gordon collected over a thousand shanties and sea songs on the waterfront in San Francisco and Oakland. In 1923, Gordon began editing the column Old Songs that Men Have Sung in the pulp magazine Adventure. In the column, he printed songs requested by readers and asked readers to submit additional texts and verses, and in doing so built a robust collection of folk songs. In 1925, he embarked on a year-long research trip with the goal of creating the definitive collection of American folksong. During this time he collected songs in Asheville, North Carolina, and Darien, Georgia.
In 1928, the Librarian of Congress, Herbert Putnam, appointed Gordon as a "specialist and consultant in the field of Folk Song and Literature" in the Music Division. Later, Gordon adopted the title of director of the Archive of American Folk-Song. During this time, Gordon continued to live and conduct research in Darien, Georgia. In 1929, at the request of Putnam and Carl Engel, chief of the Music Division, Gordon concluded his fieldwork and moved to Washington, D.C. While in D.C., Gordon experimented with recording apparatuses and conducted his own tests with wax cylinders, wire recorders, and disc recorders. In 1933, dwindling funds and dissatisfaction with Gordon's performance led to the end of his tenure as the Director of the Archive of American Folk-Song. He continued to work as an editor and professor of English until he passed away in 1961.
Scope and Content
The collection comprises song texts, correspondence, publications, and field notes collected by Robert Winslow Gordon over the course of his career as a folklorist. The bulk of the collection includes correspondence and songs contributed by readers to the Old Songs that Men Have Sung column in Adventures Magazine, edited by Gordon. Also included are song texts from Gordon's fieldwork as well as song texts collected by others and given to Robert Winslow Gordon. Gordon also collected published music books, serials, magazines, and article reprints and these materials are included as part of his papers alongside his professional correspondence and field notes. Gordon spent the end of his life compiling and indexing his collection, and the card catalog song index he created is also included as part of the collection.
Arrangement
The Robert Winslow Gordon papers are organized in 8 series:
Series 1: Correspondence and song texts contributed to the "Old Songs that Men Have Sung" column, Adventure Magazine, 1923-1929
Series 2: Song texts from fieldwork conducted by Robert Winslow Gordon, 1920-1925
Series 3: Song texts collected by others and acquired by Robert Winslow Gordon, 1922-1932
Series 4: "Inferno" collection, 1920-1928
Series 5: Published music, 1862-1932 (bulk: 1919-1932)
Series 6: Published serials, magazines, and reprints, 1840-1932 (bulk: 1910-1932)
Series 7: Correspondence and notes, 1914-1961 (bulk: 1920-1932)
Series 8: Card catalog, undated
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Frothingham, Robert, 1865-1937; Gordon, Robert Winslow; Henry, Mellinger Edward, 1873-1946; Johnson, Guy Benton, 1901-1991; Odum, Howard Washington, 1884-1954; Winger, Betty Bush
Subjects
Bawdy songs.; Folk music--California.; Folk music--Georgia.; Folk music--North Carolina.; Folk music--United States.; Sea songs.; Songs--Texts.
Titles
Adventure (New York, N.Y.)
Form/Genre
Correspondence.; Folk song texts.; Manuscripts.; Song texts.
Container List
- Series 1: Correspondence and song texts contributed to Old Songs that Men Have Sung, Adventure Magazine, 1923-1929
  Approximately 3,858 letters containing songs and queries contributed to Robert Winslow Gordon in his role as editor of the Old Songs That Men Have Sung column in Adventure Magazine between 1923 and 1929.
  - Subseries 1: Originals
    - Song texts 1-32, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Song texts 33-60, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Song texts 61-90, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Song texts 91-120, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 1/4)
    - Song texts 121-150, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 1/5)
    - Song texts 151-180, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Song texts 181-216, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 1/7)
    - Song texts 218-255, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Song texts 260-295, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Song texts 296-330, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 2/3)
    - Song texts 331-360, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Song texts 361-393, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 2/5)
    - Song texts 394-420, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Song texts 421-450, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Song texts 451-470, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Song texts 471-510, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Song texts 511-540, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Song texts 541-570, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Song texts 571-600, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Song texts 601-630, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Song texts 631-654, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 4/1)
    - Song texts 655-680, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Song texts 681-704, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 4/3)
    - Song texts 706-730, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Song texts 731-755, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 4/5)
    - Song texts 756-780, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Song texts 781-804, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Song texts 805-830, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Song texts 831-850, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 5/2)
    - Song texts 851-874, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 5/3)
    - Song texts 875-900, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 5/4)
    - Song texts 901-920, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 5/5)
    - Song texts 921-945, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 5/6)
    - Song texts 946-975, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 5/7)
    - Song texts 976-1005, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 6/1)
    - Song texts 1006-1035, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 6/2)
    - Song texts 1036-1065, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 6/3)
    - Song texts 1066-1099, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 6/4)
    - Song texts 1100-1130, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 6/5)
    - Song texts 1131-1162, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 6/6)
    - Song texts 1163-1173, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 6/7)
    - Song texts 1174-1205, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 7/1)
    - Song texts 1206-1235, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 7/2)
    - Song texts 1236-1270, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 7/3)
    - Song texts 1271-1305, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 7/4)
    - Song texts 1306-1345, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 7/5)
    - Song texts 1346-1385, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 7/6)
    - Song texts 1386-1410, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 7/7)
    - Song texts 1411-1450, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 8/1)
    - Song texts 1451-1490, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 8/2)
    - Song texts 1491-1520, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 8/3)
    - Song texts 1521-1549, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 8/4)
    - Song texts 1550-1575, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 8/5)
    - Song texts 1576-1605, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 8/6)
    - Song texts 1606-1622, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 8/7)
    - Song texts 1623-1650, 1923-1929, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 9/1)
    - Song texts 1651-1679, 1923-1929, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 9/2)
    - Song texts 1680-1710, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 9/3)
    - Song texts 1711-1740, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 9/4)
    - Song texts 1741-1779, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 9/5)
    - Song texts 1780-1810, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 9/6)
    - Song texts 1811-1849, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 9/7)
    - Song texts 1850-1878, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 10/1)
    - Song texts 1879-1909, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 10/2)
    - Song texts 1910-1949, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 10/3)
    - Song texts 1950-1989, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 10/4)
    - Song texts 1990-2037, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 10/5)
    - Song texts 2038-2089, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 10/6)
    - Song texts 2090-2115, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 10/7)
    - Song texts 2116-2154, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 11/1)
    - Song texts 2155-2195, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 11/2)
    - Song texts 2196-2239, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 11/3)
    - Song texts 2240-2289, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 11/4)
    - Song texts 2290-2329, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 11/5)
    - Song texts 2330-2359, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 11/6)
    - Song texts 2360-2399, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 11/7)
    - Song texts 2400-2430, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 12/1)
    - Song texts 2431-2459, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 12/2)
    - Song texts 2460-2497, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 12/3)
    - Song texts 2498-2539, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 12/4)
    - Song texts 2540-2569, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 12/5)
    - Song texts 2570-2609, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 12/6)
    - Song texts 2610-2639, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 12/7)
    - Song texts 2640-2669, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 13/1)
    - Song texts 2670-2699, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 13/2)
    - Song texts 2700-2729, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 13/3)
    - Song texts 2730-2759, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 13/4)
    - Song texts 2760-2779, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 13/5)
    - Song texts 2780-2809, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 13/6)
    - Song texts 2810-2849, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 13/7)
    - Song texts 2850-3025, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 14/1)
    - Song texts 3026-3059, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 14/2)
    - Song texts 3060-3106, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 14/3)
    - Song texts 3107-3165, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 14/4)
    - Song texts 3166-3219, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 14/5)
    - Song texts 3220-3255, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 14/6)
    - Song texts 3256-3289, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 14/7)
    - Song texts 3290-3319, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 15/1)
    - Song texts 3320-3349, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 15/2)
    - Song texts 3350-3379, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 15/3)
    - Song texts 3380-3409, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 15/4)
    - Song texts 3410-3439, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 15/5)
    - Song texts 3440-3469, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 15/6)
    - Song texts 3470-3509, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 15/7)
    - Song texts 3510-3539, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 16/1)
    - Song texts 3540-3569, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 16/2)
    - Song texts 3570-3599, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 16/3)
    - Song texts 3600-3708, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 16/4)
    - Song texts 3709-3753, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 16/5)
    - Song texts 3754-3798, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 16/6)
    - Song texts 3799-3858, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 16/7)
    - Song texts unnumbered>, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/1)
    - Song texts unnumbered, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/2)
    - Inventory, Part 1, pages 1-90, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/3)
    - Inventory, Part 2, pages 1-100, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/4)
    - Inventory, Part 2, pages 101-200, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/5)
    - Inventory, Part 2, pages 201-254, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/6)
  - Subseries 2: Typescript carbons, 1923-1929
    - Song texts 1-99, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/7)
    - Song texts 100-199, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/8)
    - Song texts 200-299, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/9)
    - Song texts 300-399, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 17/10)
    - Song texts 400-499, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 18/1)
    - Song texts 500-599, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 18/2)
    - Song texts 600-699, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 18/3)
    - Song texts 700-799, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 18/4)
    - Song texts 800-899, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 18/5)
    - Song texts 900-999, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 18/6)
    - Song texts 1000-1099, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 18/7)
    - Song texts 1100-1199, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 18/8)
    - Song texts 1200-1299, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 18/9)
    - Song texts 1300-1399, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 18/10)
    - Song texts 1400-1499, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 18/11)
    - Song texts 1500-1599, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 19/1)
    - Song texts 1600-1699, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 19/2)
    - Song texts 1700-1799, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 19/3)
    - Song texts 1800-1899, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 19/4)
    - Song texts 1900-1999, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 19/5)
    - Song texts 2000-2099, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 19/6)
    - Song texts 2100-2199, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 19/7)
    - Song texts 2200-2299, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 19/8)
    - Song texts 2300-2399, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 19/9)
    - Song texts 2400-2499, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 19/10)
    - Song texts 2500-2599, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 19/11)
    - Song texts 2600-2699, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 20/1)
    - Song texts 2700-2799, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 20/2)
    - Song texts 2800-2899, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 20/3)
    - Song texts 3000-3099, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 20/4)
    - Song texts 3100-3199, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 20/5)
    - Song texts 3200-3299, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 20/6)
    - Song texts 3300-3399, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 20/7)
    - Song texts 3400-3499, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 20/8)
    - Song texts 3500-3599, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 20/9)
    - Song texts 3600-3699, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 20/10)
    - Song texts 3700-3799, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 20/11)
    - Song texts 3800-3899, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 21/1)
    - Song texts, unnumbered, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Correspondents list, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 21/3)
- Series 2: Song texts from fieldwork conducted by Robert Winslow Gordon, 1920-1925
  - Subseries 1: California, circa 1920-1923
    Approximately 150 songs and groups of texts collected by Robert Winslow Gordon while he lived in California between 1920 and 1923. The first songs correspond with cylinder recordings 1-131.
    - Manuscripts 252-376, 409, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 21/4)
  - Subseries 2: North Carolina, October-December 1925
    Approximately 374 songs collected by Robert Winslow Gordon during a field trip to North Carolina between October and December 1925. Texts 1-298 correspond with cylinder recordings A1-A202.
    - Original typescript, 1-130, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 21/5)
    - Original typescript, 131-260, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 21/6)
    - Original typescript, 261-389, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 21/7)
    - Original typescript, only recorded songs A1-A202, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 21/8)
    - NC 1-NC 82, Carbons, A1-A50, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 21/9)
    - NC 83-NC 144, Carbons, A51-A99, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 21/10)
    - NC 146-NC 224, Carbons, A100-A150, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 21/11)
    - NC 225-NC 298, Carbons, A151-A202, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 21/12)
    - NC 299- NC389, Carbons, A201?, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 21/13)
- Series 3: Song texts collected by others and acquired by Robert Winslow Gordon, 1922-1932
  - Subseries 1: J.P. Boyd manuscripts, 1926-1927
    Approximately 125 songs collected by J.P. Boyd in Alliance, North Carolina between 1926 and 1927.
    - Original typescript, 1-136, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 22/1)
  - Subseries 2: R.M. Davids manuscripts, circa 1924
    Approximately 33 songs collected by R.M. Davids in Woodmere, Florida, circa 1924. Given to Robert Winslow Gordon by Joanna Colcord in New York, New York in December 1929.
    - Originals, with index, 1-38, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 22/2)
    - Typescript and carbons, 1-33, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 22/3)
  - Subseries 3: Robert Frothingham manuscripts, 1922-1923
    Approximately 137 letters containing queries and songs for Robert Frothingham, editor of the Old Songs that Men Have Sung column of Adventure Magazine, 1922-1923 as well as correspondence to and from Frothingham while he was editor.
    - Adventure Magazine correspondence, A-H, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 22/4)
    - Adventure Magazine correspondence, I-M, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 22/5)
    - Adventure Magazine correspondence, N-S, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 22/6)
    - Adventure Magazine correspondence, T-Z, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 22/7)
    - Originals, 1-137, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 22/8)
    - Typescript, 2-137, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 22/9)
    - Carbons, 1-137, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 22/10)
  - Subseries 4: J.H. Hanford manuscripts, 1930
    Approximately 8 songs collected by J.H. Hanford from Esther Stover in Cleveland, Ohio in January 1930. Stover learned the songs from her father in Iowa City, Iowa.
    - Originals, 1-8, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 23/1)
    - Typescripts and carbons, 1-8, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 23/2)
  - Subseries 5: Mellinger Edward Henry manuscripts, 1928-1929
    Approximately 61 southern Appalachian songs collected by Mellinger Edward Henry of Ridgewood, New Jersey in 1928-1929. Most texts and headnotes were subsequently published by Henry in the Journal of American Folklore and in Folk-Songs from the Southern Highlands.
    - Typescripts, 1-60, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 23/3)
    - Carbons, 1-60, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 23/4)
  - Subseries 6: Guy B. Johnson manuscripts, circa 1929
    Approximately 15 songs contributed by Guy B. Johnson of the University of North Carolina, circa 1929. Written down by Walter Jordon of New York, as he learned them in the American South in 1909.
    - Originals, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 23/5)
    - Typescripts and carbons, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 23/6)
  - Subseries 7: Mary Newcomb manuscripts, 1929-1930
    Photostat manuscript entitled Songs My Mother Sang, containing 210 texts and 101 tunes from New Hope, Kentucky, contributed by Mary Newcomb of Louisville, Kentucky from 1929-1930.
    - Typescripts, 1-50, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 23/7)
    - Typescripts, 51-102, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 23/8)
  - Subseries 8: Howard W. Odum and J.D. Arthur manuscripts, 1929